Welcome to the aerospace manufacturing factory
If you want to do aerospace
first
You need to buy a few large CNC machines first.
Wait a minute there's another one called flame spraying
This is something you generally won’t see in the factory.
So how do we appreciate those
The cuties who usually spread rumors are slapped twice.
That is, we have to use scientific experiments
First, the first Challenger No. 1
like firecrackers
So don’t really think that
That is, how many processing machines do you have?
Or you have some simple processing equipment
You can do aerospace
Actually, these are two different things.
Hi guys
Welcome to Super Serious Boy
We talked a lot about tool mother machines before
When CNC and various processing processes
Did we mention it in it?
aerospace
Everyone must be very interested in the word aerospace.
You think it's very special, right?
Not every company
They can all be involved in the aerospace industry.
Look at this cute airplane LOGO
Today we are going to show you all
An aerospace company?
Let's go
Make airplanes Make airplanes
fly to the sky
When talking about the aerospace industry
Let me give you a correct idea first
you know aerospace it's a
An industry with extremely low error tolerance
It is also a means of transportation
Locomotives, cars, motorcycles, boats
What about these means of transportation?
Found a tripod
If the car is on the road today
Engine stalls
What should I do if the cylinder shrinks?
It doesn't matter
parked on the roadside
What to do if a tire blows out
Just park on the side of the road
If the ship's engines were retracted today
It doesn't matter
Just float on the sea
But what if it’s an airplane?
it if the engine fails today
Or landing gear
it's hurt
You go there when you land
That's not for you to drift over there
A state that allows you to wait over there
So today if your company
If you want to do aerospace industry
it is being processed
As long as your processing is not careful
When there is a slight stress failure
Put your landing gear down again
that moment
You may cause a lot of disasters
So in an industry like aerospace
it is in addition to your previous manufacturing
beyond being able to do well
At the same time
Later look-back period
Compared with other industries
It will take longer and longer
before we get on the elevator
Have you seen this?
Mitsubishi Heavy Industries
Excellent cooperating factory
Previously on our channel
Have you introduced it to everyone?
It is actually a very large military company
Then what
You know Honda
They actually make HondaJet
It's that little plane
Then we will talk about it before entering
Before the aerospace company manufactured
Let me first give you a concept of aircraft manufacturing.
When we are taking a plane
You can divide it into single aisle and double aisle
dual-aisle aircraft
Its carrying capacity is relatively large
What about single-aisle planes?
It’s possible that many of us have it
Go abroad to play
Traveling on a business trip
It's the one you often get
As long as you have someone who often goes abroad
You must have seen it
There are so many different airlines
But what about the whole world?
There are probably more than 5,000 airlines
But you know the whole world can make airplanes
Assembling aircraft
How many rooms are there?
Actually, there are only about five or six rooms.
inside
Contains two largest rooms
The Boeing you have heard of
And the airbus
These two probably account for
-95%
And of course Embraer
What ATR
But the main and biggest
These are the two Boeing and Airbus
Basically the plane you take
Most of them are these two
And Taiwan
It's actually better than you think
Even more powerful
What about Taiwan?
Have done a lot
Providing this to the aviation industry around the world
Regardless of its material
Structural parts
Electronic components
Composites for aircraft
landing gear
Then the avionics
Just all kinds of things
In fact, Taiwan provides them all
Then what
Can't take it off
It seems that I can only transfer the whole thing.
you see
There are so many types of aircraft
from the smallest
one seater
two seater
Then spray pesticides?
Then maybe go all the way to the single aisle?
It's a double aisle
There are probably two types of airplanes that you see in Taiwan.
One is called business Jet
When I was in Liman, France
on that racing track
The event is over
What about us?
Others will have to take the minibus
It takes about seven or eight hours to get to the airport.
But there are some big bosses nearby
They just fly on a private plane
Directly next to Le Mans' runway
Take off directly, leave directly
Their time is very expensive
And another kind
I'm going to take a ride
It's called Commercial Aircraft
It's the plane we usually take.
Probably below this row
Commercial passenger aircraft with more than 100 passengers
you can draw a line
Then it looks like this
of course
In Taiwan you will see it called Regional Jet
It's the kind where there are less than 100 people
between regions
small flying
Fly from Taichung to Penghu
Fly from Taipei to Taitung
It's relatively short-distance
It's not like you're going to cross the entire route.
So as I said along the way
You are in a whole Showroom
You'll see a lot of these parts
But what about these parts?
It is similar to normal
Where we are CNC machining
Or parts made in a milling machine
What's the difference
The most important difference is
It needs to be able to backtrack
Just treat me as this part and this material
After I'm done
Suppose something happens to it one day
Then we need to trace back which company made this thing?
Which material is it made of?
Are there any problems with the processing procedures?
cause some of the damage it creates
Or the problem that caused it
like this
Just a small airplane landing gear
You know airplane landing gear
Its materials also branch into many kinds
Has humankind evolved in the past?
First materials science
After humans were known to use fire
Entering the metal age
What about after the metal age?
We have advanced to the point where we can synthesize various metals
on this road
The material itself is constantly improving
Processing is also improving at the same time.
Take the weight we usually use when flying as an example.
when taking off
when it lands
This is the most dangerous time in all of aviation
So if this is processed above
A little crack occurred
Can you imagine the landing gear of an airplane
When it takes off and lands
How much weight does it have to bear?
Guess what
-3 2
-300 tons
Congratulations on guessing wrong
About 500 tons
Let's just find the thinnest side here.
If there is a crack here
It is possible that in that moment of 500 tons of weight
It will break directly
Then the whole thing is touching
Or it broke when taking off
You can't land
Funny
So an A350
The following wheels
Just sitting there empty weighs about 300 tons.
But what about when it takes off and lands?
The impact of that moment
It also needs to be more than 500 tons
So at this time you make the landing gear
It must be able to withstand a weight of 500 tons
Otherwise, all of you on the plane
Then they will all see God directly
That’s why many people in the market actually say
Working in aerospace
It is actually a high-tech industry
The most important thing is statistics
These long-term data
with them in the process of processing
Need 100% full inspection
Although it has many processing processes
It looks like it will be the same as a normal inheritance
It looks similar
But you can imagine
it is actually a
It is actually an industry that does not allow for mistakes
This is an industry called honesty culture
like mobile phone iPhone
Do we have to pursue the latest system every year?
Latest software
fastest speed
But your iPhone must have crashed before?
Or maybe your APP has also been used as a
Although it is also a high-tech industry
But how about comparing it in aerospace?
That's what we would rather
Don’t use the fastest and latest version, which will cause crashes easily.
Even if it only
-10% 5% crash chance
Not allowed
We would rather make a very, extremely stable system
Make it 100% inappropriate
Can't follow the problem
What about this?
It's in your aerospace company
It’s something that must be learned
So an engine
Basically you do it
You can make money for 30 or 50 years
won't change
Because there is no need to change
I want stability
To be traceable
When this plane flies for 30 years
What about after the accident in the last year?
I need to be able to find this company to settle the accounts
So in fact, aerospace companies
You can think of it as
It's not like some high-tech stocks
Will suddenly explode
you know
If it were on the market today,
It is a very long-term and stable
Because it must be able to withstand
There is a 30-year retrospective period
As long as his company employees
honest
Or when I'm processing
I think something is weird
I really want to report it to the police
So if you are a very honest person today
I highly recommend you
You can work at an aerospace processing company
Then we will enter the production line
In fact, just now we
Inside this shot
There are some things that are military secrets
Anyway, I didn’t say it
You shouldn't know what's confidential, right?
did you see this
yellowed small poster design
CFM56-7 SAC
Inside the entire engine parts
They are divided into many paragraphs
There are people doing the cold part at the front
Then there are people who do the hot section at the back.
Their company is doing the hot section at the back.
It's super alloy
That is to say, it is probably used in
-Parts with temperatures above 1000 degrees
Look at the yellowing state of this poster
Just know how old this thing is
But it is no longer installed
But still flying
It has now been revised
The following content involves confidentiality.
Then you can judge for yourself
What do you think of a company?
If you can still take over the job for 2 or 30 years,
After the model change later,
Will you let it pick it up?
You can consider stocks
HondaJet
It's the one I just talked about
HondaJet aircraft
This is the first time that the United States and Japan
They worked together to develop the engine
What we do together is Business Jet
Then why is this poster placed here?
That must be it
this company
There must be something provided for it, right?
Can this be discussed?
Can speak Can speak
yes right
They did it for them
I'm just afraid of being scolded
Did you know there is a little tidbit of knowledge?
The whole world probably now
-When the A380 is retired
It's the A350
Inside the A350
It has a lot of specific parts and landing gear
Sixty percent are made in Taiwan
Single-aisle aircraft around the world
Its engine case, suspension block and specific parts
-70%
All made in Taiwan
Cool
Welcome to the aerospace manufacturing factory
If you want to do aerospace
first
You need to buy a few large CNC machines first.
Like what we shot in Japan before
Mazak
DMG MORI
Or something like these
Your workpiece can be made to an oversized size
You can walk into the CNC machine
CNC that is directly turned and milled by others
I'll let you take a look
Taiwan is not
Everyone can't afford it
But there are people who buy these machines
We usually
Didn't let anyone see it
Look inside this room
Is it bigger than your room?
A CNC bigger than your room and toilet
Maybe it looks a little small when photographed from inside the lens
But probably
six square feet
It can accommodate two beds no problem
And this company, except for some parts
Even the most dangerous landing gear in an airplane
it is also doing
This process is actually not difficult to explain.
The first is milling
then fitter
Check later
Then the special process
Clean
Recheck
Then spray paint
That's it.
sounds simple
But actually some parts are very difficult
Because first you can imagine
Suppose we take off from Taiwan
Our normal temperature is about 35 degrees
When we fly to an altitude of 30,000 to 40,000 feet
It will be about minus 40 degrees to minus 57 degrees
What happens after
Take it to another city
What about this city?
Its possible temperature will be hotter or colder
And it’s just a matter of the temperature difference and the material.
I tell you
There are many companies in Taiwan
No way to solve it
Like this one behind me
It seems like you think
Nothing
It costs 100 million
And what about the oil quenching heat treatment of this thing?
It is actually what we just did
what is said
Special process
In this factory
Come all the way from here
Go to the right
We can all call it a special process
That is, in our episode
I want to take a special photo for everyone
Something different
In addition to oil quenching
Wait a minute there's another one called flame spraying
This is something you generally won’t see in the factory.
Follow this
Does it look like in Dragon Ball?
Did Dahl
Brought from Planet Vegeta
What about this?
Vacuum heat treatment furnace
And next to it
There is another thing called
Atmospheric heat treatment furnace
Why do this?
because
NADCAP
It is actually authenticating
Whether you are processing welding or heat treatment
chemical processing
Any manufacturing of composite materials
In fact, it is through this
Third party inspection and certification
go check
Is it OK or not?
Can it carry so many lives?
Fly to an altitude of 30,000 feet
But 30 years ago
There is no such thing
30年前就有飛機了嘛
So each production chain and supplier
Everyone wants it
Send it to Boeing for certification
Then take it to the airbus
Send to GE for certification
That would be very troublesome
So the U.S. Department of Defense
It’s integrated
This is what all aerospace companies need
Turn it into a certification called NADCAP
You know NADCAP is involved
Is it like Michelin?
Michelin certification
One Michelin star?
Then Michelin three stars?
Samsung is like the concept of gold medal
The Shengtian we came to today
By next year 2025
It is the first in Taiwan
The only manufacturer with five gold medals
So if you go online today
I saw some people writing that
If you have a few CNCs, it’s called aerospace.
The one called stupid doesn't understand
Do you think it's so easy to do?
Then I'll be an astronaut
Special process
another thing
You probably rarely see it
Where is this thing?
It's called bead hitting
You can go inside and take a look
you can see it on the ground
inside
There are many cone-shaped floors
grid by grid
It seems to be collecting something
This one above is
Landing gear parts
What is bead hitting?
It just uses small steel balls one by one
small beads
Hit it with crazy squirts inside
Hit this titanium metal
Sometimes
It is made of high strength steel
Sometimes titanium alloy
The impact of the beads is very strong
If you hang a pig today
hit it with a bead
It will be beaten until it becomes like a pig
So
That's what we want
sacrifice a camera
put inside
Or sacrifice a colleague
Record it in there for everyone to see
Let me show it to you
What does this bead look like?
What about this bead I’m holding on to now?
It's 230
There is also a bead called 330
Its size is different
Can’t you tell how big it is?
I specially took three of them to show you.
Did you see there are three in my hand?
This is 330
This is 230
The small one in the middle is 170
Why do we need to divide the size of beads?
Because of the size of the beads
As long as it's different
Its MTV is different
Do you know how to convert impact force?
V is its acceleration
M is the quality of this thing
And what about the T above?
is its contact time
So F is equal to M divided by T times V
You can calculate the impact of this F
Wrong words
Tell me in the message below
Now that you know the size of this bead,
Paired with mechanical arm
In order to comply with this labor law, we
Let’s show it to you in a synthetic way
Then why use this bead?
How about spraying its surface?
In fact, this is a
A method of surface strengthening treatment
You can think of it as
Just take a very small hammer
Then tap on it evenly like this
Like forging
Every time you forge
It will change the collision of this material
It also produces heat energy
At the same time
It will also change the arrangement of this intensity.
And this thing is the same as sandblasting
Actually it's something different
Let me show you this warning
aerospace manufacturing industry
Making mistakes is not a sin
Hiding a mistake is a sin
If you make a mistake or discover an error
Please notify your supervisor immediately
This is your responsibility
Because if it hits with light arm
If it creates a small crack
Your family happened to be on that flight
Landing gear down
When it's about to fall
It happens to be because of that crack
sin
Another special process
Basically everyone has never seen it
It’s called high-speed flame spraying
Not a high-speed mother-in-law
Looks like this
If you are in aerospace
Or make semiconductors
you are inside
You will find that the sound is different
Beyond the sound of water
Do you feel like my voice is being sucked out of you?
The place inside looks like a recording studio
Because when the fire is on inside
It will be super noisy
will be like this
Very few people in Taiwan know this thing
Very few people are learning
But I think it’s not bad to learn this thing
Just because
Why don't you do aeronautics?
Why do we make semiconductors?
This technology can be used
If you want to learn this technology
Find him
He has no apprentice now
no apprentice
You can learn from him
So what exactly is high-speed flame spraying?
It is different from the spray paint we usually see.
Or is it the powder paint we saw?
The same thing is heating
It's the same, there are some and some are missing.
What's the difference?
In fact, you can think of it as
To replace electroplating
When I was doing chrome plating,
It is not a very environmentally friendly thing
So in fact, high-speed flame spraying
What about its manufacturing process?
You can think of it like a
metal coating
Spray it on the workpiece you want
So why can it be used to replace chrome plating?
Because in addition to environmental protection
It can supplement the meat
And it can be a little more than chrome plating
Its durability and wear resistance
It's better than chrome plating
So what does it look like when it sprays?
Let me peel one off and show it to everyone.
This thing
Carbide
You see, after knocking it, there will be this sound
So this thing is similar to what we saw this morning
Organic chemical coatings
What's the difference?
The difference is here
What’s the difference??
Aerospace is all about flying
it must be able to withstand
Resistant to corrosion and temperature differences
Also scratch-resistant
So usually when we finish spraying a test piece?
You will take this
go cut it
Known in the world of martial arts
Hundred grid test
There is a cute little part in Baige Experiment
It just holds a utility knife
Or holding a hundred-square knife
Then cut it one by one like this
Cut four times
So it’s 100 squares
hundred grid test
no no no
The main purpose of the hundred grid test is to test it
The adhesion of the coating
So after it cuts it with a knife
It's stuck on top with tape
tear it up
Then tear it up
Then it won't fall off
Then why is it called Baige?
That's because it's like
It looks like plaid clothes when cut
yes
like clothes
Therefore, it is commonly known as the hundred grid test.
We're talking about this
At this point in time
The heat treatment is almost done
We can take everyone to see it
Is heat treatment useful or useless?
What is the general heat treatment and oil quenching heat treatment?
There is also vacuum heat treatment
What is the difference?
What about this time?
Folks actually have different opinions
But what?
How do we verify the facts?
We can send it directly to the laboratory
Go get everyone tested
After all, you have to trust the material
believe in science
I believe Dr. Chao
Laboratory
Master Azai has told you
If you want to blow the air conditioner at work
Come to the laboratory
Do you know what's inside the laboratory?
There are so many things it needs to store
Like the two of us just now
Inside that oil-quenched furnace
How to prove it
The oil quenching of my furnace is OK.
We will put a sample or test stick next to it
use the same material
same temperature
The same oil quenching method
then keep it
What about aerospace companies like this?
Documents and information
That's which furnace it was made in at that time
What kind of material is it made of?
What kind of processing did it undergo?
this thing
It will last for 50 years
Just let people trace it back
Then we just did two
One is oil-quenched
One is vacuum
How to test its tolerance
Who is taller?
You can place bets on our live broadcast now
The vacuum is relatively high
Do you think the vacuum is higher?
What do you think about following Dar?
Those who came together in the space capsule were relatively high.
But that oil quenching cost 100 million
So what are you betting on?
I think it's oil quenching
I bet on oil quenching
Ah, are you using Threads?
Do you know that in the past
There are many ways to oil quench.
Someone use that salt
Did someone insert it into the soil?
Then someone said something
Just take a pig
Then after that is forged
Then insert it into the pig's body
Pull it out again
The properties of that lard oil
Then let it cool down
But materials used in aerospace
Of course you can't use it like this
This kind of experience value of the old master
There are many ways to quench
And our channel has filmed some before
But these two types today are relatively rare.
So how do we appreciate those
The cuties who usually spread rumors are slapped twice.
That is, we have to use scientific experiments
First, the first Challenger No. 1
vacuum treated
Where is this test stick?
is its different thickness
The number of pounds it can pull is different from the tonnage.
You can use this basis of physics
Let's do some calculations
What diameter do you want?
Approximately how long will it take?
It must be within an acceptable range
How much does the boss want to pull today?
This one is 130kN
About 13 tons
Let's bet
Just like the number that broke and stopped.
-82kN
You catch
-80 kN
Then I have 81kN
Do you want to press?
If you guess correctly, your salary will be increased by 10%
-81 kN
-81 No, I just said it
-83kN
How do you think our company gets a salary increase?
Our company's salary increases are all obtained through gambling.
you do not know
ok come on
-83.1124kN
Who guesses right?
-83kN
Sorry
-83.11kN
More than 83kN
No
Fix it
-82.8624kN
Sorry
-82kN
It depends on whether the breaking point is good or not.
Come, give everyone another chance
It was a vacuum just now
We are now changing the oil and quenching
That stick we just pulled
The test stick also looks like this
But why does it become crooked when pulled to the middle?
because of the discontinuity in it
In fact, it's a little thinner
We just want it to break in the middle
So it’s thinner in the middle
so wait a minute
When we pull the deformation
It's the middle section
here
midway
Can't you tell?
Awesome
My eyes are vernier calipers
Okay, how much is it?
datum point
Let’s have a benchmark
-100...
-170kN
Give you another chance to raise your salary
It’s the end of the year soon
-160kN
OK, come and replace you
-169kN
-172kN
your height
right
you
-167kN
Bottom oil quenching and vacuum heat treatment
Which one will be stronger?
Let’s first make some experimental data with you
Show it to everyone
Let’s all make a judgment again
like firecrackers
-169
-169kN
Mount Tai
Right
wow congratulations
congratulations
This year I will add 10%
The value just mentioned was 168kN.
The numerical value is written as 168kN. Sorry.
So it's interesting
You see, it still touches when you pull it apart.
Then it explodes like a flame
In fact, a steel
it has been treated differently
the pulling force it can withstand
It will be completely different from the stress it bears.
So you mean oil quenching is better?
Actually it's not like this
I tell you
Do aerospace
It’s just different from DIY cannons.
The most troublesome part about aviation is that
These two materials
In fact, it is different in itself
The first one to pull was 4340
The material model of the second pull is 300M
The most interesting thing about aerospace is that
As long as you use this model
It's in the regulations
You just have to use a vacuum
Still must be quenched with oil?
So suppose
if it were the same material today
In fact, vacuum air quenching and oil quenching are used
The effect it actually achieves
The pulling force achieved is exactly the same
it just cares about being
Today you have to take the high-speed train to Taipei
Or do you have to take the bus to Taipei?
Or do you have to drive to Taipei by yourself?
But why does it stipulate these things?
during heat treatment
its curve
That is, they all have to be within their standard values.
So don’t really think that
That is, how many processing machines do you have?
Or you have some simple processing equipment
You can do aerospace
Actually, these are two different things.
So today if your company can receive these two people
It’s the supply chain of the industry within the company.
Basically every value you have
No matter how hard you are
Then maybe your tensile test?
Or maybe it’s the test piece you included in the material?
You all need to be regulated and recorded
And then everything is contained in this
Okay, that’s pretty much it for this episode.
At the end of this episode
Let me show you this boss
How much does he like buying equipment?
In addition to those made with this special process
What about these devices on the right side?
Please look at the left half
have you ever thought about
a boss
Like to buy equipment
Buy a chemical tank
Buy them all by yourself
Whether you want to do passivation?
Make an anode
Do an acid etching test?
You can see it all in this factory
So you can see the back
Is there any
Rinse tank
You can already go up and wash it off
It feels like you can take a hot spring bath when you go up there.
If you are interested in this episode
Please encourage this boss
We often come to shoot photos
In any process we are talking about today
Any questions?
You are welcome to ask us in the message area below
If your company is confident
Make sure your stuff is made
All can be tested 100%
You're welcome too
Join the aerospace industry
The equipment we all saw today
Just tens of billions
Their company is listed on the OTC market
Their company has stocks that you can buy
If you still want to see what
Interesting and strange company
You are also welcome to leave a message below to tell me
Hope this episode
There is knowledge that allows you to add some strange processes
Then we'll see you next week
Goodbye
Build an airplane Build an airplane
you know before
There is a talent show
It means everyone will be popular
Learn from Jam Hsiao and sing about building an airplane
Build an airplane Build an airplane
Fly to the green meadow
Squat down Squat down
I make airplane wings
You can sing it to the chairman later
You know their chairman
With their company?
It was opened by the teacher and the students together.
one day
I'm halfway through class
tell the teacher
teacher
Let's open a company
Teacher, please stop teaching.
Come out and open a company with me.
Then students and teachers
Just set up a company
So in their company
many people inside
They were all taught by this teacher
I forgot who was looking for whom
Anyway, together
Then come out and open a company
So in this company
you can swear
But the only thing you can't scold is